RICHARD AJADI

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An MSc Mathematics graduate with extensive experience using mathematical concepts and computing skills to teach Mathematics concisely. I was tasked with preparing young students to gain admission into Tertiary institutions in Nigeria, coaching them to pass Mathematics and Further Mathematics in the West African Senior School Certificate Examination (WASSCE). I also have about 5 months of experience as a Cover Teacher here in the UK.

EDUCATION

MSc Mathematics, University of Chester, Oct 2021 – Oct 2022

Grade: (MERIT)

MODULES LEARNT: Partial Differential Equations, Stochastic Calculus, Numerical Convergence and stability Theory, Mathematical Ecology, Functional Analysis, Research Methods & ICT for Mathematics

DISSERTATION: STEFAN MOVING BOUNDARY PROBLEM

- Studied and analysed the change in temperature at the boundary of each domain.
- Studied its application in determining the optimal stopping time for holding an asset in a financial market.

BSc Mathematics, University of Ilorin, (NIGERIA), Oct 2021 – Oct 2022

CGPA: (4.15)

THESIS: APPLICATION OF (FDM) TO SECOND ORDER PARTIAL DIFFERENTIAL EQUATION

COMPUTING AND TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ✓ MATLAB
- ✓ Writing and recording of scientific results using LATEX
- ✓ Currently enrolled in the IBM Professional Data Science Certification, where Programs such as **R**, **Python** and **SQL** are being used to analyse Data.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Chester, Cheshire +(44) 7765117884 ajadioluwarichard@gmail.com

REFERENCE

Available upon request

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Cover Teacher: (Teacher Active), Liverpool, UK

- Provided cover for Teachers around schools in Merseyside, where I ensured regular class activities were not interrupted.
- Marked the class registers, ensured students attended their classes and most importantly, reported any concerns to the appropriate authority.

Mathematics Teacher: (Grande-Ville Academy), Abuja, Nigeria Nov 2019 – July 2021

- ❖ I was tasked with the duty of preparing students to pass the West African Senior Certificate Examination (WAEC)
- ❖ I oversaw the Mathematics Club, where we taught students how to reason logically by introducing them to games like chess.

Platoon Leader & Footballer: NYSC (Voluntary), NIGERIA Nov 2018 – Nov 2019

- ❖ In charge of the welfare of over 200 corps members in my platoon during the mandatory National Youth Service in Nigeria for recent graduates.
- Co-operated with the Platoon commandant, Officers, and other Platoon leaders to organize daily events, social activities, personal drills, sporting activities and match passes.
- ❖ I was part of the best corps members who were selected to play for the NYSC National Football team for the remainder of the service year.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Mental health support work: (MHC-UK) $Feb\ 2023-Till$ Date

- Provided support and care for residents with learning disabilities and Autism.
- Helped in planning and recording daily activities undertaken by the service users.

ACHIEVEMENT

Recipient of the Mobile Technology Network (MTN) Science and Technology Scholarship in Nigeria (2015 – 2018)

